Hasan Hajjar



Remotely and Dubai

Q

+963933912076 WhatsApp

hasanhajjar535@gmail.com

Aleppo/Syria (Current Address) 🜐

Summary

Experienced Dot Net Developer with +5 years of experience and demonstrated history of working in telecommunications, medical, manufacturing, continuous integration and banking. Skilled in Laravel, .Net, C#, Databases and Front-End technologies. worked on 10+ projects for SQL database design. Developed and maintained over 20 .NET websites with 100% client satisfaction.

Education

I graduated from high school in 2014. An approximate rate of 96%.

I graduated from Aleppo University, Faculty of Informatics Engineering, this year. At an approximate rate of 80%.

During my university studies, I studied several levels at the University's Consulting Institute of Languages, and I reached the seventh level out of 10 levels.

I learned and followed many lessons and courses for programming and its applications.

She was awarded the University's Al-Basel Award for Excellence in 2016. My grades in mathematics were excellent.

Qualification:

Bachelor of Engineering, Informatics Engineering

Aleppo University - Aleppo, Syria 2022

Experience

average experience in all:

2018-2019

Web developer • member of team • Alzahraa company

2019–2021

Web developer• team leader and programmer • Mayar.World (Remotely)

2017-2022

Special instructor • my Office • Hajjar Academy

During my first job as a programmer, I faced many challenges

Such as learning to deal with Laravel, databases and its engines such as Oracle and MySQL

But I have achieved many achievements, such as the Aleppo Water Site, where I was a contributor to it as my first site...

During my second job with MayarWorld, he learned to manage the project team. I faced many challenges and obstacles because it was the first time I was the leader of the software work team....

But I learned more skills. Troubleshoot and Solve +10 issues in the web appusing two languages (php & c#).

Excellent in working with ASP.NET C# MVC.

.Net Web Developer Develop, Integrate and test new modules and components in .net C#/ASP Web development environment. Transfer system knowledge and experience to the team to Facilitate high level of development and support services.

Performs troubleshooting and analysis of application issues.

Summary Skills

- 1. PHP => laravel 90%
- 2. C# => ASP.NET 90%
- 3. .net core
- 4. WordPress
- 5. Python=> Django flask
- 6. Node-JS
- HTML5 C\$\$3 REACT Java\$cript – jQuery -Bootstrap
- MySQL Sql Server Oracle mongo DB – SQL Lite – Maria DB
- 9. Redis
- 10. Java C++ C# Python
- 11. Android (java)
- 12. API and REST API
- 13. System Analyst
- 14. Data entry
- 15. Git and GitHub
- 16. design all UML diagrms
- 17. class diagrams- DFS
- 18. Object diagram
- 19. UML sequence diagram
- 20. I can deal with tools for UML
- 21. use case diagram
- 22. Deal with Net Logo
- 23. OOP
- 24. Algorithms
- 25. Design patterns
- 26. MVVM MVC

As a fellow member of the application development team, I evaluate and study new available software technologies to help keep the services of the software department up-to-date.

- Testing feature phone and smart phone software, try to find out the bugs and make sure every function in the phone able to run correctly.
- Development and execution of test cases
- Support research department to solve software bugs.
- I have the experience and knowledge in: computer software and hardware installation, web design, graphic design, mobile applications Android & e-commerce web development.

Experience in creating API solutions.

Basic design skills: including user interface design, user experience, prototyping and scalability

Capabilities

- Strong skills in Core Java, server-side Java technologies, and Spring frameworks.
- Extensive experience in software design, architecture, development integration.
- I see my ideal self and able to work independently and as a leader to help guide/train other application developers so that over time they improve their knowledge using back-end technologies.
- Translate functional requirements from business users into sound technical/application designs that meet business objectives.
- Work closely with project managers and developers to manage the project and ensure smooth implementation.
- Alignment with other team members, code review and proficiency with deployment best practices.
- Perform impact analysis/regression testing prior to QA

I am flexible to work with the team remotely.

- Manage the repository of code and documentation for the project in various development environments.
- I participate in setting implementation schedules, system implementation planning, and implementation.
 - meet with system users to understand the scope of projects
 - work with software developers and project support teams
 - monitor applications and software systems
 - carry out stress testing, performance testing, functional testing and scalability testing
 - write and execute test scripts
 - run manual and automated tests
 - test in different environments including web and mobile
 - write bug reports
 - assess code
 - · carry out resource planning
 - review documentation
 - · work towards departmental and project deadlines
 - provide quality assurance
 - provide objective feedback to software development project teams
 - troubleshoot and problem solve
 - design tests to mitigate risk
 - present findings to software development and business user teams

Links

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hasan-hajjar-8236bb222

GitHub:

https://github.com/hajjar-developer

Telegram:

https://t.me/hasanshajjar

Languages

Arabic 100% (native) English 90% (written/spoken) French 50% (written)

Job Type: Full-time

Some of my Works:

Web site for my company in 2018-2019: http://aleppowater.gov.sy/

Web site for my company in 2020-2021: https://www.mayar.world/

- travel to different project sites
- work on multiple projects at one time
- document analysis
- liaise with project teams in other parts of the world
- communicate findings to technical and non-technical colleagues.

Develop applications for various projects according to the company's internal requirements and customer requirements.

Application maintenance and troubleshooting for direct projects including user support.

Design and maintenance of databases for various internal applications.

Maintenance of application servers and database servers.

Deal with Microsoft SOL Server database systems.

Mobile Application Development for Android

Integration interfaces such as APIs and web services.

- Ability to prioritize tasks and execute them effectively in a fast-paced, high-pressure environment
- Driven and hardworking personality with strong analytical and problem solving skills
- A proactive individual willing to take on any project with enthusiasm
- Detail-oriented and resourceful with a desire to learn
- Ability to maintain a high level of accuracy in the performance of all essential duties
- Ability to think strategically to support technology projects in the business Collaboration with the ability to work with other business functions in the organization
- •Ability to communicate technical information to non-technical personnel.
- Ability to work independently and with limited direction, when needed
- Ability to handle pressure and meet deadlines
- Manage the complete software development process from concept to publication
- Maintain and update the following software spread
- Lifecycle management from start to finish for production software and applications
- Supervising and directing analysis, writing and construction,

Publishing software

- Development of the front end site architecture.
- Designing user interactions on web pages.
- Development of back-end website applications.
- Create servers and databases for jobs.
- Ensure optimization across mobile platforms.
- Ensure that applications are responsive.
- Work together with graphic designers to design websites features.
- Vision through a project from conception to completion product.
- Design and development of application programming interfaces.
- Meet the technical and consumer needs.
- Keeping abreast of developments in web applications and programming languages.
- Supervising automated testing and providing feedback to management during the development process
- Modify and test previously developed changes software.

Knowledge about JIRA.

Other skills

I can to be a member of the application development team. I can to be primarily responsible for performing application design, coding, testing and documentation using the .Net C# (C sharp), or any requested programming language and the mostly famous relational database like Microsoft SQL server (Stored Procedure).

- strong verbal and written communication skills with the ability to liaise with a variety of stakeholders
- problem-solving skills
- the ability to work under pressure
- I attention to detail
- competent technical skills
- the ability to work in a team and individually
- organizational skills with the capability of working towards tight deadlines
- a passion for working with technology.

Strong Skills

Strong skills in the area of designing, coding and testing using C#, ASP.NET MVC, Entity framework and LINQ

Self-motivated individual who's a team player, yet able to work independently, Sharp at understanding requirements and finding risks,

- Excellent verbal communication skills.
- Good problem solving skills.

Front end site architecture development.

Audit code to identify and fix performance bottlenecks.

Designing user interactions on web pages.

Development of back-end website applications.

Create servers and database schemas.

Work alongside graphic designers for web design features.

Vision through a project from concept to finished product.

Design and development of application programming interfaces.

Create secure and well-tested APIs for sharing sensitive data throughout the application.

Meet both technical and consumer needs.

Keeping abreast of developments in web applications and programming languages.

Critical thinker and good problem solver.

- Great analytical and problem solving skills with strong presentation and leadership skills.
- Strong directing skills, ability to adapt and work with team members of various types.
- Levels of experience including strong communication and conflict resolution skills.

Familiar with PHP, object-oriented programing, and common design modes such as MVC.

- Familiar with common MVC framework of PHP, preferably Larayel.
- Have good coding habits, codes need to be structurally clear, standardized naming, be highly logical, low redundancy rate, and ability to solve problems within a short time frame.
- Consciously optimizes projects, self-driven to optimize codes and database of developmenting projects.
- Record test progress and results. Streamline overall testing processes. Identify, isolate, and track bugs throughout testing. Identify any potential problems that users might encounter. Review user interfaces for consistency and functionality. one years of QA Testing experience. Experience using JIRA or similar tools.